Hemang Shah

iOS Engineer

hemangshah.in@gmail.com

Summary

More than six years of extensive experience. I can read, write and code in Swift, Objective-C, and Java.

Good team player and leader with "Let's Do" attitude. Excellent communication skills.

Self-starter, keen to adapt to new technologies and to upgrade skills.

Experience

Consultant at RAKSYS INDIA

April 2017 - Present

Working as Mobile Consultant (iOS) to build the apps which can be helpful to the citizens, residents, and the Government of Ras al Khaimah, UAE.

Self Employed at Freelancer

May 2016 - March 2017 (11 months)

During the period of 11 months of self-employment, I worked with various clients to work on their projects. Starting from requirements understanding, designing, development, quality assurance and finally deploy it on to the AppStore and future maintenance.

Key Highlights of the work and experience as a self-employed:

- Networking with the clients.
- Project Discussion Understanding of the requirements.
- Documentation Object Oriented Diagrams.
- Providing the full features list, further steps, and development cost.
- Development of the native iOS apps.
- Custom designing for the iOS apps.
- Handling junior developers with the assigned projects in different technologies.
- All the client communications over Skype chats, emails, and calls.
- Thoroughly responsible for the project undertaken from A to Z.

I worked with various clients from Upwork.com, Freelancer.com, Elance.com, oDesk.com, and local companies.

Notable Achievement:

- Worked on-site as iOS Consultant for the EGA (Electronic Government Authority), a department of the Government of Ras al Khaimah, UAE. through a contract from the Tecnics Integration Technologies Private Limited, Hyderabad. for the duration of 1 month and completed one of the tight deadline project with improvements and new features requirements.

Sr. Software Engineer at Azilen Technologies Pvt Ltd

December 2015 - May 2016 (6 months)

I worked there for a very short duration but it was one of the wonderful experience to work in an AGILE culture and a core team for an individual project.

Being a part of the core team of one of the companies project I was responsible to develop a native iOS application from scratch along with another developer in the team.

I have also fixed and refactored the N number of lines of code in the existing apps with the same nature and made them available to the production for the respective clients.

Key Highlights to working with Azilen:

- Learn how to work with a core team.
- Learn and use the project management tool. Mostly work in JIRA.
- Learn to follow the AGILE methodologies in SDLC.
- Be a part of the stand-up meetings on regular basis.

Company website: https://www.azilen.com

Sr. iOS Developer at AGILE Infoways Pvt Ltd

September 2014 - November 2015 (1 year 3 months)

AGILE Infoways Pvt. Ltd. given me so many opportunities and help me to know more inner skills inside me. A splendid 13 months of working with the company and a knowledgeful team of native iOS developers – a team of more than 15 people at that time was very helpful to me in future roles.

Key Highlights to working with AGILE Infoway:

- Learn and used SVN and Github.
- Worked on a small/high scaled projects, handling solely and worked as a team.

- Client communications over Call/Chats.
- Learn to work with hourly rates set by the clients to complete various tasks within the time frame.
- Became an iOS Trainer until I worked there and help learn iOS from scratch to about 30 students.
- Officially went to various universities and colleges to conduct meetups, tests, interviews, and finalize selection of the students for the Training and employment with the company.

Company website: http://www.agileinfoways.com

Sr. iOS Developer at iMOBDEV Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

January 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 9 months)

iMobDev Technologies Pvt. Ltd. is the company in which I placed through our college campus placement drive. 6 fellow (and friends) got selected through the campus placement out of 200 (approx.) students. It is the place where I first-time learned to code in Objective-C and eventually I preferred to become an iOS Developer.

Key Highlights to working with iMobDev Technologies:

- Learn how to code in Objective-C.
- Learn all the fundamentals of iOS frameworks.
- Client communications over email and Skype Chat.
- Regular Updates on the Project to/from clients.
- Custom Web Tool to handle the current task, project, and overall timeline of my work.

Company website: https://www.imobdevtech.com

Software Engineer

June 2007 - August 2007 (3 months)

I worked there as a Visual Basic 6.0 developer and developed 3 inventory & education software for the clients in Bhavnagar City (My hometown). I worked there on my vacation after the 2nd year during the graduation.

Company website: http://apexsoftwarehouse.com

Education

L.J. Institute Of Engineering and Technology

MCA, Computer Applications, 2009 - 2013

Shree Swaminarayan College of Computer Science

BCA, Computer Applications, 2006 - 2009

Shree Daxina Murti Vinay Mandir

Primary and Higher Secondary Schooling Education, 1993 - 2006

Hemang Shah

iOS Engineer

hemangshah.in@gmail.com



Contact Hemang on LinkedIn